Guide to the Earl Y. Henderson papers, 1916-1931
Henderson, Earl Y. papers, 1916-1931
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Earl Y. Henderson papers, 1916-1931
9059
Earl Y. Henderson
11 folders
Correspondence, typescripts.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence to and from Henderson, Indian reports written and collected by Henderson.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Henderson was the Assistant Secretary of the Board of Indian Commissioners. McDowell was Secretary of the Board of Indian Commissioners. Burke was commissioner of the Office of Indian Affairs.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence to and from Henderson and Indian reports written and collected by Henderson.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Burke, Charles H.; McDowell, Malcolm; United States. Board of Indian Commissioners.; United States. Office of Indian Affairs.; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Cherokee Indian Agency (N.C.); United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Crow Indian Agency.; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Lower Brulé Agency.; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Taholah Indian Agency.; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Tulalip Agency.; United States. Office of Indian Affairs. Western Shoshone Agency.
Subjects:
Indians of North America.; Indians of North America Arizona.; Indians of North America Mississippi.; Indians of North America New Mexico.; Indians of North America South Dakota.; Indians of North America Washington.; Acoma Indians.; Cherokee Indians.; Choctaw Indians.; Crow Indians.; Havasupai Indians.; Paiute Indians.; Shoshoni Indians.; Yuma Indians.
Places:
Acoma (N.M.); Camp Sheridan (Ala.); Colorado River Indian Reservation (Ariz. and Calif.); Crow Creek Indian Reservation (S.D.); Fort Hall (Idaho: Fort); Fort Mojave Indian Reservation.; Fort Yuma Reservation (Ariz. and Calif.); Havasupai Reservation (Ariz.); Neah Bay (Wash.); Supai (Ariz.); Walker River Reservation (Nev.)
INFORMATION FOR USERS
PROVENANCE
Huntington Free Library purchase. Gift to HFL from Marc Fleisher.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Original Huntington Free Library box numbers have been retained. Box contains multiple unrelated collections. Folder numbers pertain to this specific collection only and are not folder order for the entire box.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Folder 1:
Series II. Publications
Folder 2
Series III. Notes, Manuscripts, Map
Folders 3, 4
Series IV. Reports
Folders 5-11:
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Malcolm McDowell Camp Sheridan, Montgomery, Alabama, 1918 (Box 9, Folder 9059-1)
  - Army experiences (Box 9, Folder 9059-1)
  - Hospitalization, 1916 (Box 9, Folder 9059-1)
- Series II. Publications
  - The Havasupai Indian Agency, Arizona, 1928, 1929, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 9059-2)
  - The Supai Trail, 1929
  - Plan of Reorganization of the United States Indian Service, 1925
- Series III. Notes, Manuscripts, Maps
  - Washington Notes (Box 9, Folder 9059-3)
  - Lands of Indians in the State of Washington West of the Cascade Mountains (Box 9, Folder 9059-3)
  - Map of the Fort Hall Reservation, Idaho, ca. 1915 (Box 9, Folder 9059-3)
  - Notes on Isleta Pueblo, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 9059-4)
  - Notes on Acoma Pueblo, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 9059-4)
- Series IV. Reports
  - Report on the Crow Creek and Lower Brule Indian Reservations, South Dakota, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 9059-5)
  - Report on the Cherokee Indian Reservation, North Carolina, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 9059-5)
  - Report on the Choctaw Indians of Mississippi, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 9059-5)
  - The Indian Bureau from 1824 to 1924 (Box 9, Folder 9059-5)
  - Report on the Cherokee Indians of North Carolina, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 9059-6)
  - Report on the Choctaws of Mississippi, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 9059-6)
  - Report on the Havasupai Indian Agency, Arizona, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 9059-7)
  - Report on the Truxton Canyon Indian Agenxy, Arizona, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 9059-7)
  - Report on the Colorado River Indian Agency and the Fort Mojave Indian School, Arizona, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 9059-7)
  - Report on the Fort Yuma Indian Agenxy, California, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 9059-7)
  - Report on the Neah Bay Indian Agency, Washington, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 9059-8)
  - Report on the Taholah Indian Agenxy, Washington, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 9059-8)
  - Report on the Tulalip Indian Agency, Washington, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 9059-9)
  - Report on the Nonreservation Indians Under the Carson Agency, Nevada, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 9059-9)
  - Report on the Walker River Indian Agency, Nevada, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 9059-10)
  - Report on the Western Shoshone Indian Reservation, Nevada, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 9059-10)
  - Report on the Paiute Indian Agency, Utah, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 9059-11)
  - Report on the Sells Indian Agency, Arizona, 1931 (Box 9, Folder 9059-11)